# **RUBEN OTERO LAMELA**

#### **PERSONAL STATEMENT:**

Specialised in customer service with 10 years' experience in this field, resolving problems and adapting to different customers politely and with confidence. A calm, positive attitude which enables prioritizing objectives, communicating effectively, setting concrete expectations and maintaining control. Accommodating customer needs through common sense and attention to detail. Extensive knowledge of recruitment, training and development of staff.

#### **PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES:**

Fluent in English (C1)
Fluent in Spanish (Mother Tongue)
Years of experience in talent acquisition and HR activities
Excellent team player
Strong customer service orientation

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:**

## 03.2020 - 04.2022 Marportsunbeach S.L Beach bar Restaurant. Spain

- Challenging job during the last two years making this beach bar a reference for customers from all over the world, by offering high quality food and exceptional customer service.
- Due to the pandemic situation we had to run this place with very talented and hard working members of Staff.
- Contributing with all our knowdlege to create the perfect menu and deliver the best standars was crucial in order to attract the few tourists in the area.
- Setting high standards and creating a solid structure to maintain the business afloat and make it thrive in the following years.

# 01.2019 - 01.2020 HMRC (Surge Rapid Response Team)

- Recruitment of Staff for different sectors of HMRC
- Managing casework from a variety of different departments.
- Using and maintaining multiple government databases.
- Answer customers' queries over the phone, face to face, through letters/emails or using social media.
- Developing collaborative relationships with colleagues throughout Government.
- Assisting with high profile 'rapid response' deployments, and predictable peaks in demand.
- Helping to foster a 'continuous improvement' ethos throughout the team.

# 06.2012 - 11.2018 Wagamama Cardiff Library, United Kingdom FOH Team Member, FOH Manager (Head of Recruitment)

- Ensuring Health & Safety and also hygiene procedures & standards are maintained
- Responsible for recruiting using an internal applicat tracking system.
- Running interviews, trial shifts and inductions.
- Training & developing managers, team leaders and FOH team members.
- Reducing business costs by improving retencion and engagement of the staff.
- Looking closely at the KPIs of the restaurant and elavorating reports for the Area Managers.
- Dealing with complex issues throught the shift and resolving problems in order to improve the service and increase sales.
- Maximising all business opportunities to drive sales and meet targets.
- Organising the daily and weekly rotas for the Restaurant's staff.
- Controlling stock levels and placing orders through fourthfnb.
- Daily Staff Briefing Session.
- Dealing with customer complaints through a CRM System.

# **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS:**

09.2021 – ongoing	A1-C1 German language course Online.
09.2018 – 06.2020	A-Level equivalent ('Bachillerato') in History, Latin, Economics, English, French and Philosophy. IES La Eria and IES Dna Jimena
09.2014 – 06.2015	Cambridge English: Advanced certificate (CAE), Cardiff and Vale College, United Kingdom
09.2005 – 06.2007	Diploma in Computer System (Hardware and Software) Seresco, Oviedo, Spain
09.2003 – 06.2005	A-Level equivalent ('Bachillerato') in History, Latin, Economics, English, French and Philosophy. IES La Eria and IES Dna Jimena, Asturias, Spain